<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Linode Engineering</title>
		<description>Blog posts from Linode engineerings about engineering at Linode</description>		
		<link>https://engineering.linode.com</link>
		<atom:link href="https://engineering.linode.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>API Alpha Events Rollout</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of the new API has never been to rewrite the same software with new technology.
We intend to come out of this project with a new application that accomplishes the same legacy tasks,
but has been designed from 13 years of practical experience.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>https://engineering.linode.com/2016/11/10/Events.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://engineering.linode.com/2016/11/10/Events.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Redesigning Endpoints, Creating Linodes with Backup Service, and Rebuilding Linodes</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting how some of the biggest challenges we sometimes face as programmers
have nothing to do with programming. Creating great products takes us beyond
the ones and zeros and requires us to think more like “normal” people.
&lt;em&gt;How&lt;/em&gt; will it be used? How can we make it &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt;? Can we solve the age-old problem
of making a product easier for our customers and still maintain good design principles
at the same time?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>https://engineering.linode.com/2016/09/19/Redesigning-Endpoints-Backups-Rebuilding.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://engineering.linode.com/2016/09/19/Redesigning-Endpoints-Backups-Rebuilding.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Taking Risks - API Labels and Prefixes Rollback</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Part of the intention behind development of the Linode API v4 Public Alpha 
has been to try new
ideas and get feedback before customers are dependant on the API for their
day-to-day work. This gives us the freedom to take risks we would
otherwise shy away from without fear of long-term consequences if
they didn’t pan out. If we didn’t end up rolling back at least once experimental
feature, we would have missed the whole point and I wouldn’t be writing a blog post
like this.  But we took a risk - and missed. So, with a heavy heart,
I must announce a rollback and confirm that we have removed “labels” from most
endpoints in the API.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>https://engineering.linode.com/2016/08/31/Taking-Risks.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://engineering.linode.com/2016/08/31/Taking-Risks.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Connecting our API to Redux with higher-order functions</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;In our work on the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.linode.com/2016/05/16/Announcing-the-new-open-source-manager.html&quot;&gt;new Linode Manager&lt;/a&gt;,
we’ve put some effort into finding reusable ways to manage information from our
API with the Manager’s Redux store. We ended up building a module that uses
higher order functions to generate Redux reducers and action creators for this
purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>https://engineering.linode.com/2016/08/17/Using-metaprogramming-in-the-manager.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://engineering.linode.com/2016/08/17/Using-metaprogramming-in-the-manager.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>IP Addresses in the Alpha API</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;In our latest development rollout of the Alpha API, we’ve started adding
networking capabilities, beginning with public and private IPs for your Linodes.
This means both IP types will soon be available in the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Linode/manager&quot; title=&quot;new Linode
Manager&quot;&gt;new Linode Manager&lt;/a&gt; sometime in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>https://engineering.linode.com/2016/08/14/Managing-IP-Addresses.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://engineering.linode.com/2016/08/14/Managing-IP-Addresses.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>API Alpha Label Rollout</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;After two more weeks of brain power and coffee, we have another fresh batch of
updates for the API V4 Alpha!  This time around we’ve put a lot of effort into
rolling out labels for the majority of resources that didn’t use them, as well as
some bug fixes and assorted improvements.  We’ve also laid the foundation for
upcoming features.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>https://engineering.linode.com/2016/07/26/Labels-Rollout.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://engineering.linode.com/2016/07/26/Labels-Rollout.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>API Alpha upgrades Plan, adds Labels, improves Backups, UTC</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;We are proud to announce another round of features and improvements to the
API Alpha. With this release, we’re upgrading the test Linode plan,
doing even more cool things with Backups in our API Alpha environment,
adding labels, and changing how time works. We’ve also added some
capacity to our API Alpha environment, as it keeps growing in popularity!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>https://engineering.linode.com/2016/07/07/Alpha-adds-labels-backups-utc.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://engineering.linode.com/2016/07/07/Alpha-adds-labels-backups-utc.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Backups Added to API Alpha</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;As development of the new API progresses in tandem with our work on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.linode.com/2016/05/26/Getting-started-with-the-new-manager.html&quot;&gt;the new
manager&lt;/a&gt;,
we wanted to introduce functionality that our Linode manager has but our current API does not.
Backups seemed to be the logical choice, and we’re pleased to announce that its
initial integration - enabling, restoring from backups, and snapshots - is now
live and available for alpha consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>https://engineering.linode.com/2016/06/22/Backups-Added-6-22-2016.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://engineering.linode.com/2016/06/22/Backups-Added-6-22-2016.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How we picked a comfortable frontend stack and settled into its ecosystem</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;In the JavaScript world today there are tons of shiny new projects out there and
it’s overwhelming to figure out how to build a large product from the ground up.
Before starting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Linode/manager&quot;&gt;the new Linode Manager&lt;/a&gt;,
we had a long period of internal prototyping and developer discussions to find
the ideal frontend stack for the project. Three main prototypes emerged, based
on &lt;a href=&quot;http://facebook.github.io/react/&quot;&gt;React.js&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://angularjs.org/&quot;&gt;Angular&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mithril.js.org/&quot;&gt;Mithril&lt;/a&gt;. Each
of these platforms ships a different broader design philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>https://engineering.linode.com/2016/06/03/Building-a-comfy-frontend-stack.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://engineering.linode.com/2016/06/03/Building-a-comfy-frontend-stack.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Getting started with the new Manager</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;As you may have &lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.linode.com/2016/05/16/Announcing-the-new-open-source-manager.html&quot;&gt;seen&lt;/a&gt;,
the new Linode Manager is an entirely static app being developed in the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/linode/manager&quot;&gt;open&lt;/a&gt; on Github. This post will walk you
through the steps required to get the new Manager up and running on your local
machine. This process can also be extended to building any application on the
new API.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>https://engineering.linode.com/2016/05/26/Getting-started-with-the-new-manager.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://engineering.linode.com/2016/05/26/Getting-started-with-the-new-manager.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
